A Guide to the Sara Teasdale Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8170-d
Sara Teasdale Collection 1888-1934
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8170-d
ca. 700 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research
Acquisition Information
Purchase 1986 July 18
Item Listing
- MANUSCRIPTS
  - Vine Colby
    - "To the Ghost of a Player" by Vine Colby, written in memory of Lawrence Hanley, n.d.; AMs,; 3 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 1)
    - "Wishmakers' Hill" by Vine Colby, 1910 Nov 26; AMs, 9 p. on 9 l. (Box Box 1)
  - Celia Ellen Harris
    - "Ave Frater!" by Celia Ellen Harris, 1912 Apr 14; TMs, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
  - Margaret Scott Lawler
    - "War: As it Affected Our Town," by Margaret Scott Lawler, 1923 Sep 18; TMs, 20 p. on 10 l. (Box Box 1)
  - Paul Janis
    - "Carcassonne" by Nadaud, written in French by Paul Janis for Vine Colby McCasland, [1932]; AMs, 3 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 1)
  - Williamina Parrish
    - "Lines on a Deceased Frog" by Williamina Parrish, n.d.; AMsS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 1)
    - "Meecho" by Williamina Parrish, 1929; TMs, 5 p. on 5 l. (Box Box 1)
    - "Meecho: A Ditty for Betty by Widdy" by Williamina Parrish, n.d.; TMs, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 1)
    - "Scraps" by Williamina Parrish, 1933; TMsS, 75 p. (Box Box 1)
    - " Sara Teasdale--A Memory. by one who shared Youth with her..." by Williamina Parrish, 1933; TMsS, (3 copies) (Box Box 1)
  - Frances S. Porcher
    - "The Potters and the Potters' Wheel," The Mirror, by Frances S. Porcher, 1905; TMs, 6 p. on 6 l. (Box Box 1)
  - Sara Teasdale
    - Christina Rossetti: An Intimate Portrait by Sara Teasdale, with holograph Prefatory Note and revisions by the author, 1932; TMsS, 62 p. (Box Box 1)
    - "The Philosopher" by Sara Teasdale, ca. 1910; TMs, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
    - Poem beginning "Oh baby who shall come to us..." by Sara Teasdale, presenting a baby ring to Barbara George, 1908 Jan 28; AMsS, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
  - Patience Worth
    - "Betty" by Patience Worth, n.d.; TMsS, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
    - "Betty" by Patience Worth, n.d.; TMsS, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
    - "Lamento Doloroso" by Patience Worth, dedicated to Williamina Parrish, n.d.; TMs, 19 p. on 19 l. (Box Box 1)
    - "Miss Aggie" by Patience Worth, n.d.; TMsS, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
    - "Resurrection" by Patience Worth, 1926 Easter; TMs, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
    - " William Marion Reedy" by Patience Worth, n.d.; TMsS, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
    - Poem beginning "And there, at the path's end,..." by Patience Worth, TMsS, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
    - Poem beginning "He who hath announced himself my Brother..." by Patience Worth, n.d.; TMsS, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
    - Poem beginning "I was weary...sore weary..." by Patience Worth, 1925 Feb; TMsS, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
    - Poem beginning "Never may I see a moonlight white..." by Patience Worth, 1928; TMs, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 1)
    - Poem beginning "Oh, I have heard..." by Patience Worth, 1924 Sep; TMs, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Poem beginning "The dust's on the rose,..." to Miss Ferris, n.d.; AMs, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
    - "The Sand on the Bathroom Floor", AMs, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 1)
    - "Triolets" lessons on Marion Cummings Stanley and Sara Teasdale, 1909 Jan; AMsS, (8 items) (Box Box 1)
- LETTERS
  - Sara Teasdale, Madrid, Spain, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1905 Feb 3; APCS (Box Box 2)
  - Sara Teasdale, Alger, Algeria, Africa, to Caroline Risque, St. Louis, Missouri, 1905 Feb 8; APCS (Box Box 2)
  - Sara Teasdale, Cairo, Egypt, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1905 Mar 8; APCS (Box Box 2)
  - Sara Teasdale, Rome, Italy, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1905 Mar 25; APCS (Box Box 2)
  - Sara Teasdale, Paris, France, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1905 Apr 1; APCS (Box Box 2)
  - Jennie M.A. Jones, Chicago, Illinois, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1905 Aug 19; APCS (Box Box 2)
  - Jennie M.A. Jones, Chicago, Illinois, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1906 Apr 30; APCS (Box Box 2)
  - Jennie M.A. Jones, Chicago, Illinois, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1906 June 28; APCS (Box Box 2)
  - Jennie M.A. Jones, Chicago, Illinois, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, [1906]; APCS (Box Box 2)
  - Susan Creighton Williams, St. Louis, Missouri, to Wilhelmina [sic] (Williamina Parrish, St. Louis, Missouri, 1906 Oct 6; ANS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    sending thanks for her sympathy and inviting her to visit
  - Sara Teasdale, San Antonio, Texas, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Feb 24; APCS (Box Box 2)
  - [Sara Teasdale] to [Vine Colby], 1907 Feb; APC (Box Box 2)
  - George W. Teasdale, On board S.S. Cretic, Off Sardinia, Italy, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 May 21; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    revealing his delight in a poem she sent and discussing her style
  - Sara Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 July 11; APCS (Box Box 2)
    re looking over proofs to her volume of poetry [
    Sonnets to Duse and Other Poems
    ]
  - Sara Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 July 14; APCS (Box Box 2)
    mentioning her E[leanora] D[use] sonnet being accepted by
    Poet Lore
    for publication
  - Sara Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 July 18; APCS (Box Box 2)
    re horseback riding and critiquing a poem, "Vengeance" by Colby
  - Sara Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Aug 20; APCS (Box Box 2)
    mentioning the July
    Potter's Wheel
  - Williamina Parrish, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Sep 14; ALS, 6 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    sending her a review of Sara Teasdale's volume of poetry
    Sonnets to Duse...
  - Lillie Rose Ernst, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Sep 18; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    praising her book
  - Thomas B. Mosher, Portland, Maine, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Sep 18; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 2)
    extending his thanks for the copy of her book
    and hoping for its success
  - Elizabeth M. Brown, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Sep 19; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    thanking her for the copy of her book
    , praising it, and wishing for its success
  - Caroline White McKinney, Memphis, Tennessee, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Sep 19; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    revealing her pride of her childhood friend ( Sara Teasdale) after seeing her "Guenevere" in
    The Digest
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Sep 21; TLS, 2 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 2)
    expressing his pleasure in presenting her poem ["Guenevere"] to the world, praising her book of verses,
    , and encouraging her to continue writing verses in her careful fashion
  - Will J. Thornton, The Buckingham, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, Missouri, 1907 Sep 24; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    praising her poem ["Guenevere"]
  - Fred R. Macauley, Colorado Springs, Colorado, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Sep 26; ALS, 10 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    praising her effort, and mentioning seeing actress Olga Nethersole.
  - Frances S. Porcher, Webster Groves, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Sep 28; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    thanking her for the autograph copy of her book
    , writing about getting settled in their new home
  - Celia Ellen Harris, Hotel Berlin, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Sep; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 2)
    asking for a day to visit, expressing her pleasure in her ( Sara Teasdale's ) book
    , with ALS from Mary D. Harris to Sara Teasdale, expressing her pride in Teasdale and her book
  - Arthur Symons, Wittersham, Kent, England, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Oct 4; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    writing about the beauty of her poems and that he has written a review of her book [
  - Lee B. Hildebrand, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Oct 5; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    praising her book [
  - Arthur Symons, Rye, England, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Oct 9; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    sending his review of her book [
    ] from
    The Saturday Review
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, 1907 Oct 14; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    concerning her delight in receiving a letter from Arthur Symons, and saying that Symons is "not only one of the greatest living critics, but...a poet of true feeling..."
  - Julia Marlowe, London, England, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, 1907 Oct 17; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    thanking her for the copy of her book [
    ], and discussing Arthur Symons
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, 1907 Oct 17; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    enclosing the "notice by Arthur Symons from
    Saturday Review
    "
  - "Sue & Kate," Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Oct 19; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    thanking her for the presentation copy of her book [Sonnets to Duse...] and praising her poems and sonnets
  - Louise McNair, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Oct 31; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
  - J.P. Greene, President, William Jewell College, Liberty, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Nov 5; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box)
    ], and encouraging her to pursue her gift of writing verse
  - Marie Isabel Miller, Alton, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Nov 12; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    expressing appreciation of the copy of her book [
  - Mary C. Burke, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Nov 18; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    ] and wanting to see her
  - Guiseppe Masi, Administrator, Italian Dramatic Company, Paris, France, to Jerome A. Quay, American Consulate, Florence, Italy, 1907 Nov 19; AL, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    stating that Eleanora Duse would be returning to her home at 54 Via Robbia soon, sent to Sara Teasdale by Jerome A. Quay
  - Jerome A. Quay, American Consulate, Florence, Italy, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Nov 22; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    explaining the content of the November 19, 1907 letter re Eleanora Duse
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Nov 29; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    writing that he would be glad to use "The Heart's Hearth" in the Christmas issue
  - Paul Y. Tupper, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Nov 30; TLS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    ] and expressing his and his wife's enjoyment of her poetry
  - Joseph B. Gilder, Editor, Putnam's Montly, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Dec 2; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    returning her poems except for "Dusk" which he hopes will go into the January issue
  - Jerome A. Quay, American Consulate, Florence, Italy, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Dec 2; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 2)
    acknowledging receipt of her letter and copy of her book [
    ] to be forwarded to Eleanora Duse
  - Laura A. Proetz, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Dec 10; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    wishing to purchase her book of verse [
    ]as a Christmas gift
  - [ ], St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Dec 10; AL, 3 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    praising her book of verse,
    , and including a poem
  - Sidney Rogers Cook, Assistant Editor, G.P. Putnam's Sons, Putnam's Monthly, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Dec 11; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    sending a copy of her
    for her to autograph and saying that "Dusk" will be in the February issue
  - "Aunt Jennie," Cincinnati, Ohio, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Dec 13; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    thanking her for the book, [
    ], commenting on her gift for writing poetry, and wanting her parents to visit on their way from Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
  - M. Augusta Bailey, Providence, Rhode Island, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Dec 26; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    thanking her for the book [
  - "Emma," St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 Dec 30; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    ], praising the sonnets, and wishing to talk with her
  - Dorothy Colby, Ithaca, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1908 Jan 3; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    ] and relating personally to some of the poems, and discussing the relationship between a work and its artist and how they are perceived by others
  - Arthur Hornblow, Editor, The Theatre Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1908 Jan 14; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    returning her poem unused due to lack of space
  - Vine Colby to Inez (Dutro) George and Frank George, 1908 Jan; ANS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 2)
    re the birth of their baby, Barbara George
  - Frances Joseph, London, England, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1908 Feb 6; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    expressing appreciation for the book of verses [
    ] sent to Mary F. Raphael, who is not well, and saying that Mrs. Raphael has sent three autographed photographs of her pictures to Sara Teasdale
  - Marion Cummings Stanley, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1908 Feb 8; ALS, 8 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    commenting favorably on her book of verse [
    ], which she borrowed from Fred R. Macauley, referring to Sara Teasdale as having "the unmistakable lyric touch," comparing her own verse to Sara Teasdale's, and wanting to talk with her and get to know her
  - Mary F. Raphael, St. Lawrence, Ventnor, Isle of Wight, England, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1908 Mar 1; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    expressing her pleasure in Sara Teasdale's poem, "Guenevere," writing that their interpretations of Tennyson's masterpiece are very similar and that she will send a photograph of her picture of the work which illustrates this
  - The Potters, St. Louis, Missouri, to Inez (Dutro) George, Hutchinson, Kansas, 1908 Mar 4; Telegram, 1 p. (Box Box 2)
    sending congratulations for their baby, Barbara George
  - Pinkie D. McGrew, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1908 Mar 6; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
  - Agnes M. Schulenberg, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1908 Mar 6; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box)
    , and complimenting her writing
  - John Myers O'Hara, The Grunewald, New Orleans, Louisiana, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1908 Mar 8; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    acknowledging her praise for his translation of the odes and fragments of Sappho and writing that he would be glad to send her a copy, and referring to one of her poems as being of "rare beauty of thought and expression"
  - Oliver H. Campbell, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1908 Mar 9; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    expressing enjoyment of her book [
    ] and congratulating her on its success
  - John Myers O'Hara, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1908 Mar 16; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    thanking her for her book of poems [
    ] and expressing his appreciation of the dedicatory triolet to himself, giving high praise to her sonnets and comparing her admirably to Christina Rossetti, critiquing some of the poems, and giving her the original draft of "The Sleep Wind"
  - Adelia C. Arens, Detroit, Michigan, to The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, 1908 Mar 23; ALS, 2 p on 1 l. (Box Box 2)
    asking for Sara Teasdale's address in order to write for permission to set her "The Heart's Hearth" to music
  - H. Nelson Gay, Secretary and Treasurer, Keats Shelley Memorial Association, Rome, Italy, to Sara Teasdale, Cromwell Hall, Cromwell, Connecticut, 1908 Mar 26; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    acknowledging receipt of her poem dedicated to John Keats for the anniversary of his death
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, Cromwell Hall, Cromwell, Connecticut, 1908 Mar 26; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 2)
    enclosing a March 23rd letter from Adelia C. Arens and relaying praises for her Sonnet on John Keats from Elizabeth Waddell and R.E. Lee Gibson
  - Elizabeth M. Brown, O'Fallon, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale, Cromwell Hall, Cromwell, Connecticut, 1908 May 3; ALS, 6 p. on 4 l., with enclosure, w/env. (Box Box 2)
    hoping she is well and commenting on her treatments
  - William H. Hills, The Writer, Boston, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale, c/o Harper's Magazine, New York, New York, 1908 May 19; TL, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    requesting a paragraph referring to her poem, "Love in Autumn" and information about herself, with a page from his magazine
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, Cromwell Hall, Cromwell, Connecticut, 1908 [May]; APCS (Box Box 2)
    writing a note about her lines on John Keats on a postcard showing where Keats died which was sent to him from Rome, Italy
  - John Myers O'Hara, Hotel Longacre, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Cromwell Hall, Cromwell, Connecticut, 1908 July 12; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    sending along an article from
    The Evening Post
    about new books of verse which mentions Sara Teasdale's sonnet to Sappho
  - Henry C. R[ ]e, Pineorchard, Connecticut, to Sara Teasdale, Pomeroy Cottage, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1908 Aug 22; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    acknowledging receipt of her remembrance and wishing to hear her read some of her poems
  - Elizabeth McCracken, Cambridge, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1908 Oct 7; TLS, 2 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 2)
    thanking her for her letter and copy of her book,
    , saying she had already read her poems while at the home of Arthur Symons along with Julia Marlowe, and mentioning some of her favorite poems by Sara Teasdale
  - Mary Elizabeth Willard Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1908 Nov 1; Telegram (Box Box 2)
    re Sara Teasdale's impending arrival in Tucson
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, Tucson, Arizona, 1908 Dec 23; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    advising her on having
    Helen of Troy
    published
  - Sara Teasdale, Tucson, Arizona, to Inez (Dutro) George, Hutchinson, Kansas, 1909 Jan 28; APCS (Box Box 2)
    thanking her for the Christmas gift and saying she is going home next week
  - Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Feb 4; Telegram (Box Box 2)
    hoping she had a restful journey home
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1909 Feb 4; Telegram (Box Box 2)
    thanking him for his kindness and sending love to Marion Cummings Stanley
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1909 Feb 5; Telegram (Box Box 2)
    writing "passed Liberal all right"
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1909 Feb 6; Telegram (Box Box 2)
    acknowledging receipt of a package
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1909 Feb 10; APCS (Box Box 2)
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1909 Mar 10; APCS (Box Box 2)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons, Publishers, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Mar 15; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 2)
    accepting "Helen" for publication
  - Thekla Bernays, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Mar 19; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    thanking her for the copy of her book,
    , and praising it as well as her gift of writing
  - Williamina Parrish, New York, New York, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Mar 19; APCS (Box Box 2)
    chiding her for not writing
  - Harper & Brothers, Publishers, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Mar 22; TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
    relating that a Mr. Sidney Fane of London, England has asked permission to set her poem "Buried Love" to music
  - Editors, The Bookman, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Mar 23; TL, 1 p. (Box Box 2)
    accepting her poems "November" and "Vox Amoris" for publication
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Apr 6; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 3)
    asking her to read a book of poems and write a criticism of it
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Apr 12; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    commenting on the death of Algernon Charles Swinburne
  - Alice Evelyn Watson, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Apr 15; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    telling her that her poems are beautiful
  - Orrick S. Johns, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Apr 16; ALS, 6 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    writing that her poetry sings; commenting on her literary gift, her lyrical quality, and "the value of the songs,"; and, discussing the "necessity of deciding between the artificial-imagination and this other thing of simplicity in beauty-simplicity and the heart." There is much literary thought and discussion
  - Sidney Fane, Claridge House, Sevenoaks, London, England, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Apr 17; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    writing about having his songs published, including one with the words to Sara Teasdale's poem, "Buried Love"
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1909 Apr 23; APCS (Box Box 3)
    re the beauty of spring
  - Associate Editor, The Craftsman, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 May 22; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 3)
    accepting her poem, "The Prayer," for publicaton
  - Ethel M. Kelly, Hampton's Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, c/o Current Literature, New York, New York, 1909 June 5; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 3)
    showing an interest in her poem, "On the Death of Swinburne" and wishing to reproduce something of hers in one of their issues
  - Thomas C. Clark, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 June 12; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 3)
    sending a copy of one of his new songs, "A Queen of the Long Age"
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, Cromwell Hall, Cromwell, Connecticut, 1909 June 22; ALS, 3 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    discussing Witter Bynner's favorable comments on her poetry and his being with publishers Small, Maynard & Company, mentioning John Stapleton Cowley's praise of "Guenevere," and Zoe Aikin's new book
  - Thomas C. Clark, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1909 Aug 3; ALS, 3 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    ] and naming his favorites
  - Marion Cummings Stanley, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Bruce M. Stanley, Los Angeles, California, 1909 Aug 19; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    describing the peacefulness of Charlevoix and her visit with Sara Teasdale, and asking him to send some money